welcome to school the Exeter number for
additional living in this video we
looking at repeat tasks and automating
definitely extremely useful for making
box for games or pitting mundane tasks
everybody all sliders anchored available
no description but start with a couple
of nice features that collects has to
offer
first we have global hotkeys we can
listen for a certain hockey press to
change without script is doing or about
automation is running indefinitely and
we wanted to stop TX also provides us
with a large number of settings to
modify the behavior school TX the main
settings you may want to use his
movements delay which is the time taken
to move from the current mouse position
to the next mouse position but if this
is half a second or 0.5% scan rate which
is the amount of time between each
screens can for functions like white but
a photo checks about three times a
second and the labor for mass down which
is the time before a massive clicked
after moving to a quick location by the
photo it's half a second heavyset is
very 20 it will only be instant on the
next click it will then reset back to
hospice second if you want to continue
having a fast clip repeatedly said this
20 alright the folder the folder be used
to repeat kurd a specific number of
times this could be a set number like 50
all the items in a list in these two
examples we fest repeat some task five
times and in the second example we click
H patent in the list let's continue with
a calculator automation environment and
create a script that adds 15 times with
a folder with a modified his father in
our next example alright let's come over
to suck oily alright so that's come over
to securely and will copy lol original
data card we really need to copy is fast
is fast 34 sorry copy paste right so the
first thing we want to do is try setting
our master latest on defense
your settings and turn red with a
capital S dog move math delay with each
word that in the capital we want to make
that a goal to something different so
what we do is we could set that 20 and
this means that all it'll move instantly
across the screen you won't even see it
moves so you could make it must lower so
he could set to say one take one second
to move between each post on the screen
let's try 144 shop right let's create a
helpful at this time so we're going to
fall step in range open parenthesis 5
close parenthesis callin callin once
again indicates that we're gonna go and
indent 1 so everything that's intended
is going to get repeated alright so what
we're going to do is going to click +
and one so actually what we want to do
before this is when I click 14 we do
anything to copy this place down to
click and when I said its target offset
214 I came and we can copy this whole
line here is we gon be using it a couple
times and pasted inside a folder and
want to change the target all set in
this one to the possible but OK and then
on our next line inside of a fully we're
going to click one button again so we're
going to click on an entire fall it
would be a plus one plus one plus one
plus one extra as many times in our
range alright so once we're done with
all those places we're going to come
outside of a fully and we're going to
click the equal sign
get a final answer all set and gonna be
equal sign fly ok right so now we've got
a new program so we set out on mountain
move mouse to lay off to a better start
out for everything and move it normal
pace like before until we get to a
folder and everything will slow down so
you can see it repeating over and over
again and actually what we can do is we
could move this will put at the start
about document will leave one that and
another one at the top of the document
will make it instant actually no one
that will make it instant once we're
doing our calculations so we've got to
see the mass moving really slow there's
a quick stop such as and then moves on
to the calculated Press 1980 really fast
growing 00 well sorry one plus one plus
one equals like a cold so let's say this
this time we'll call this one calc three
and save i think is that right
let's give it a run run it'll move
really slowly quick start calc really
slowly back over to the bond that really
quickly and you can see just jumping
straight between the two and repeated
five times to get six for the first time
then added 15 times and hit a cozy up
six so far it's working correctly it
repeated five times never took it while
lives the Wallabies used for repeating a
block of code until a boolean expression
is false
so while the expression is true keep
repeating occurred
it's pretty simple commonly we use this
with the exists function as a returns
true or false even image exists right
but more of a script to repeat in the
add one forever and stop running the
script when we pass a global hotkey
alright so come back over and we heard
in writing
and we will remove a mass amounts to lay
just leave it as the default of 0.5% up
a global hotkey
to do this we're going to keep
everything we got here but we're gonna
get down a bit
we're going to create a boolean variable
cold running third called running and
it's gonna equal true capital T
so yes a program is running right now
we're going to define a function so it's
time to get a little bit more into the
advanced programming him but essentially
it's we use the death keywords to find a
function which is a block of cards we
want to run and will call it run cookie
and inside there were going to passing
the event and this is what is passed in
by a hot key binding so you can use it
if you wish but we're not going to be
using the event bearable ok so inside a
function we're going to go about global
global variable running and we're going
to set running to echo the capital F so
this is when this current runs were
going to stop the program and the reason
we need this is for our next lines
outside of our function we're going to
use env for environment which will turn
red dot had in lowercase capital hates
the hotkey
been currencies and the key we're going
to listen which can be anything you like
but I'm going to use key don't f 12 the
f1 key and key modifier is going to be
the Ctrl key so we're gonna have to hold
control and then press f1 key
modified modifier to turn red as well
don't control ctrl capitals come up and
then we're going to run the function Ron
what key close up a parenthesis alright
so whenever we passed that that hockey
f1 Kontrol f1 it will do our run hockey
function so tell running to be false
all right now it's set up a hooky we can
come down to a look
gonna leave everything else is it is
going to calculate and what we'll do is
let's remove this one originally so it
doesn't actually click one to start with
and instead of 40 gonna do is going to
have a while so we can remove this for
him and instead we're going to have a
while in lowercase exists so we're going
to use the exists function and while
exists and that calculator so I
calculated from up here but I think
while exists calculator and running
calculator is on screen
currently running we're going to keep
adding alright so that's really all we
need to change that while it is
repeating just like a full of is by
adding one and he set up to tell running
to stop being church which using the end
keyword it will cancel out is this still
exists but I running doesn't so that
both not sure and it will accept a
program an idol for us ok so let's save
and give it a shot so would you choose
run stock coke plus one and it will keep
going indefinitely you sit here and
watch it as long as we like to keep
adding some past five and he's going on
40 and then we can hold a control key
press f1 and Kansas and its 1000 work
successfully ok just to keep in mind and
watch out for 60 you lou has a way to
stop getting stuck in an infinite loop
which can be painful as it has control
over your mouth and sometimes your
keyboard try to avoid it with things
like a hockey like in our example or
using the exists function on a window
that can be all effort to be closed
also there's lots of visuals changing
remember to use the white or exists to
be certain things you want to click is
actually visible ok that's it for this
video we can now repeat task and use
global hotkeys in the next video will be
putting everything together to create a
simple automation scripts that will play
the free click again clicking heroes you
have any questions leave it in the
comments and I'll try to answer as best
as possible don't forget to subscribe
thanks for watching