Добро пожаловать в сикуликс руководство номер два
Основы
пользовательского интерфейса sekulix IDE
и создание первого основного скрипта
слайд сшоу можно скачать отдельно в описании к видео
with its own integrated development
environment IDE for short which is
incredibly powerful with buns you can
click to write the card for you it's not
everything school X has to offer but
it's very nice forgiveness and novice
programmers to start learning and have
fun while doing it
TX has several different types of things
that can try and match look for when
it's trying to use its functions we
refer to them as PSM are standing for
patent string match region and location
this is fairly straightforward but the
main one we're going to focus on is the
patent object patents will be the main
way that he tells the Kodiaks what to
interact with patent object contains
several pieces of information that we
use in our school the ex programs these
are an image the size of the image
similarity value and a target offset so
now you have to remember that its stores
any image
all right let's get on to creating
something let's create a simple
automation script that opens up the
calculator app and add 1+1 together they
should get a comfortable with the basics
of securely acts right so it's come over
to ask the XID so this is a great idea
looks like and you get this from running
the run school ext cmd and I just
collects photo a certain stone and you
up since it depends on May 14 need to
focus on is over here on the left we've
got to find find all wait wait vanish
exists and click double click right
click and drag drop is also a keyboard
actions that you can drop to hit the
drop-down forward just type in the text
on a type of this all start typing keys
on your keyboard type this sucks an
image then tries to text into it and
paste texts based things into a
different field alright let's get onto
first we need to go through the steps
that we would go through to open up
after Sir
I would go down to the start i cant stop
then under the search programs and files
our tight calculator calculator and then
enter that would run the calculator and
inside the calculator I wanted to do but
one plus one type 1+1 equals and we get
the answer script has been under so much
in advance to start with but let's give
it a go anyway and you'll find it's not
as hard as it looks right the first time
I do is win a click this stop so to do
that what we do is click the little
camera icon next to click and then asked
us to select an image on screen click
the star icon Stryker bucks over it'll
pop up click the Start icon vest
instruction want to click the INS the
stop button now an interesting thing is
that was a delayed for the animation
when you click so you want to make sure
it waits for this search field so to do
this but we're going to do is going to
use the wait command I'm going to click
through the camera again but this time
I'm you click it we gotta make sure he
quickly click the star concert Quick
Start icon and then we get this section
him and what we do is when I look for
this search so to do this we're going to
drag a box over the whole thing with
this bill I cannot be recognized and
wait for this to come up on screen once
it has appeared so we're going to type
some text so we are type type tell
clothes quotes + key with a capital K
dark
and tough with a capital and so that all
type a calculator to press the key and
cool so once thats typed in you want to
wait for the calculated to appear on
screen so its open up and did a
calculator calculator image is gonna
come over the IDE I'm going to wait and
wait for this calculated to appear on
screen so let's just wait to this number
pad to come up there is no wait until it
sees a number pad on screen and then
once the notepad there we want to start
clicking buttons let's click click the
camera and we want to click the one
button who dragged over the one and then
we want to click the + button drag of
the plus and then we want to click one
button again so drag of the one and then
we want to click on the equal sign so
driver the equal sign
all right sir this is our instructions
to run so we're going to click the start
button wait until the search pops up
type in calculating calc and press Enter
I'm gonna wait until the calculator
appears then click 1+1 equals and yeah
that's it should run actually get a redo
this a cosine that looks like my mouse
is hovering over top so we just delete
things back spacing and we want to click
again and wait for the images pop up and
then I'm gonna try over the top of this
a cosine make sure that the correct
awesome so let's give it a shot so we're
going to save this as we need say but
before he can run it so it can look at a
photo I'm gonna
domestically X folder and might even
create a subfolder called scripts so
inside the scripts photo we're gonna
save it so thats kool let's call it out
calc but that's gonna save it and
renamed up here in those show you where
it's stored and make it run so I'm gonna
close the calculator because otherwise
it will cause issues and that's it run
run it'll take over and start automating
as you can say I mean it to a script has
ended its run all successfully we have a
look at it and given us the answer to
what now it's interesting to see how
school exs storing the information that
we give it let's have a look at how you
might start to figure out how
schoolyards works plus it might
highlight an issue with our efficiency
rights over come back over to a folder
where restoring files so we created the
scripts folder called a calc so it's
inside here we noticed that it's got an
image for each one of those screenshots
that he took it is a little insufficient
especially when these two identical
images
all right sir we can also see that
there's a calcutta HTML file and a calc
top I file so we can open things up so I
could step up and say see motile up in
my head up and you can say it's just a
bunch of HTML occurred with the names of
curt and I pictures and this is what
school years is to make this images in
the editor so this is a text email
however the card that actually gets run
we can close this folder is the pie
files in this back this up in Petoskey
us we can see some cardio search inside
this current budget cuts and click on
image to click and all these functions
who can too
securely to serve as you can see we do
have some deficiencies with these
tickets and I think it could be made
much more efficient ok so now that we
have no idea about how to co-exist
storing images in separate files let's
talk about the last two features of a
pat similarity and target offset
currently we haven't taken advantage of
these two features as we've just use the
basic image image selection similarity
is a decimal value between 0 and one but
it's actually a percentage for example
0.5% similarity you can think of a
sensitivity 50% be something about 50%
the same as what you looking for click
that if a similarity 0.1% if we find
anything that looks about 10% the same
as what we're looking for click it then
we have target offset simply this is the
point to click on the image is the dayy
DAX offset from the center of the image
this will be immediately obvious once we
have a look at it
all right let's modify a script to use
less than half the images were used
before by using offset will also have a
fiddle with similarity alright let's
come back over to guard him so we don't
need to change out first thing we
definitely when I click the Stop button
and we didn't want to such talk but we
can start to change this weight section
here so what we can do is let's remove
these images were gonna get rid of that
that that that you get rid of all of
this I'm going to reset up a calculator
so far back up inside a calculator we
noticed that the plus the one the plus
and the Eagles bonds are all in this one
section of the area so we can do is
reaching our wait for this section to
appear on screen so this section has all
of the things that we need in it and
what we can do is we can grab the image
copy it
beacon type click open brackets based in
our image and clothes blankets then we
can click on this image
I'm gonna tell we can have a look at a
matching PVC this is a similarity to
inside the similarity can see that the
more I start to make it similar to more
objects appear on screen shots to get
pretty ridiculous so wanna keep that a
relatively high sensitivity rates are
around 75% to me when you look at Target
offset so inside a target all set we can
tell it where we want to click so what
we can do is we can say hey click the
one button so you just click inside of
an image and all set to upset the bottom
that place on the image
apply an OK and you see it has a
similarity up the top corner and a
little red mark pointing to where to
click on the image you can rinse and
repeat this so i cant i click click
button just put in a Dodge image to
remove it and paste it on your image
click on that and then we want to go to
a target all set the next hearing it
plus another plus section of the image
it apply ok make it up a click again a
star image close up the bracket press
one again we could have really copied
that other than other kurds from up
there but what does he do it and we can
talk click one more time
place tonight image was it off target
offset to the equals button this time
reply ok all right so now we're using
the same image four times so actually
cutting total program in half so if we
save this get back to follow him you
notice that we've only got three me just
now got the stop button
the search button and the calculated
area and if we run it closed the
calculator fast now if we run it hit run
and start typing coke
calculator an era
region cannot be felt
struggling to find the image let's give
it one more shot or rayon it start calc
Evans up did find it
respond plus one equals so I don't know
what they're there was maybe took too
long to open up so we send that it
worked I'm were used to top the amount
of images making out much much smaller
cool ok that's it for this video I'm
sure you can already feel the parody
fingertips the next thing we'll be
looking at is conditional automation you
have any questions leave it in the
comments and I'll try to answer as best
as possible don't forget to subscribe
thanks for watching