reacts to tour number five game example
in this video will create a simple
automation scripts to play the game
quickly heroes I picked this game
because smaller download on Steam or
even played a browser it's also fairly
simple to understand the basics
everybody have all slideshows anchored
available in the description before we
start important to talk about the low
level interaction functions physically X
this is important because when you click
faster than the Cliq function can but we
may as well look at other low-level
functions are available
mass down but so click down the
specified button mouse up which have a
button is specified will unlock the bun
no bun specified all buttons mouse move
will move the mouse to a specified place
in a patent for a location or
alternatively a specific place from its
composition specified as an X&Y offset
we hope will scroll the mouse within a
specified patent or location either up
or down and takes a number of steps on
the mouse with scroll down works just
like mass down however you can also put
a list of buttons to press down at time
t up actually takes a key goal list of
case if not specified Okies are the
least important to keep in mind
automation is a very iterative process
that often have to tweak and pull your
script in different directions to combat
unforeseen issues such as the tooltip
that appears after the masses been
hovering over bun may throw your image
recognition of the key thing to remember
is don't get to enjoy the script doesn't
work try or even on the 10th try alright
let's get into the example we won't be
spending hours on the script so well on
the ultimate three aspects of the game
clicking the monsters upgrading heroes
and moving on to the next time
alright so to come over to have a look
at how it works so this is the basic
game starts when you create a new game
of sixty years on the right here we have
the little monsters that you click into
damage to a new click them in their
health goes down and when they die you
pick up goals you can spend that golden
upgrades which is your heroes over here
on the left which will respond and
continue cooking
plating gold and then spending their own
your heroes are killed five year i mean
say that an upgrade becomes available
over here and you can click on that and
a lot of great and then you start doing
more damage than I'm going to damage
Berkeley and this continues until all of
the monsters in the zone have been
killed so here we have a doubt 1010 1010
area complete seeking continue doing
things here if you want to move on to
the next Sun indexes and provides strong
enemies and moco drops so you continue
collecting gold and leveling up yours is
continues on as you can see it's quite a
repetitive task until all of the enemies
in these aren't I killed and then we can
move on to the next one to notice that
when those enemies in a baby killed
there's this little skull icon here with
a zero to 10 which will come in handy
for knowing when way we can move on to
the next on show in a zone what we've
completed there's no school and when we
can upgrade the icons this light blue
over this doctor alright so now that we
know how it works
let's give it a reset and will start
running out for alright cool
ok the first thing I want to do is to
make a certain amount has not moved away
so we're going to care settings don't
move mouse to play
equal to zero points there is no delay
and I'm gonna create a running variable
which I'm gonna title hot cake n ice
cube is running running equals true
capital T and when I create some
variables to keep track of things that
are happening in game so let's have a
should click says he gonna be the number
of clicks to do before we check if there
needs to be any upgrades done let's have
a should should I upgrade there's gonna
be a true when we went to operate but
for those that off as false as there
isn't anything to upgrade when the game
starts and we'll have a variable called
time to bed which will keep track of how
many upgrades that we can do before we
can't do any upgrades so this will keep
track of loosely keep track of how fast
we're killing things and whether we
should move up to the next area most of
that off with alright so now let's
define a hotkey callback functions death
run cookie and we pass in the event you
want how global running and we want to
set running to the cool false
capital F ok now if created a Kovach
let's
ok environment env
had what key and we're going to the key
. f1 again same as last time an alchy
modifier going to be control again
easy to use and then have functions are
run but he added that lets get how
quickly here as winter so to do this we
gonna use a new function codes which apt
so returns the window so I'm gonna call
it see hates is going to be a clear
winner
eco switch capital any pipi to switch
cap no change color inside the Audi and
we're going to search for the app click
here as I believe it's called so the
name of the winter cold could hear the
capital C and Hayden has a space in 2008
so quick
space heroes postcards so now that we've
switched the app we can do a while so
while now she hates to cook cooking
years . has windows so while the window
visible for years and we're running I'm
going to repeat occurred right the first
thing we want to do is we want to click
because the game revolves heavily right
clicking the first thing we want to do
so would do if I should click for so
very well for is greater than those
clicks but we still need to do then
we're going to have actually what we'll
do is just click of a button click the
home button and we want to have over
something that we can use to click on so
we work on these enemies here but this
ground changes and if you remember when
clean through before the grand changes
to different patterns so we can't really
pick anything on this ground here to try
the health public health also changes so
what's something that doesn't change in
this area but we've got the mute button
down so if we have a muted or muted we
can keep it muted and select this area
here
unchanging throughout the whole the
entirety of the game so it will fit this
area and then will offset it from that
and click on the screen and we will see
how it goes now so we want to have one
suspect but struggled over a mute button
yeah we know what we want to do is be
want to check its similarity and set a
target I'll set it up to a matching
preview and we can see its matching
twice down here so we want to bump up a
similarity is made so it's only being
shown once again so I gotta at a value
of 86 percent similarity it apply all
set and as you can see was Indian in
high detail down here the button with
the scroll wheel and we want to click on
the enemy so when I click around here so
a massive offset from a button but we
know that this money I'm gonna move out
so it always look on the enemy by ok
with that setup
hovering over the top of our enemy you
know that I masses hovering over the top
of the enemy we can start clicking so
while should click for is greater than 0
and and running so here's a running the
bailout if I'm it clicks we are going to
mass
down to the capital D the capital B
button . capital L EFT so again I click
down the left mouse button close-up of
brackets then we're going to mass now
left button said button
. left and left us all in capitals
all right click the mouse down months
and lifted the mouse button up we can
say that was quick runs so should click
for can now minus equal one so we can
remove one from the total amount of
clicks and that will allow all linked to
end so outside of that while now we're
going to go back to a fast if mine and
this time we're going to do
time to dead check and whether we should
move on to the next area sir if time to
head is greater than or equal to two so
if we are able to upgrade twice without
missing an upgrade quick psycho and not
exists and thing that we want to check
if it doesn't exists
take a screenshot of clothes blankets
and clothes them and yes thing we want
to check for is that skull so we're
going to take a screenshot I'm gonna
pick the skull and because the back
banks can change we're going to try and
stay inside the confines of the skull
and get enough detail that we can pick
it out later on but they're still image
of the skull him he wanted to make sure
that we definitely have the skulls
similarity matching preview showing up a
couple of times even getting picked up
here against to clients who want to
boost up that similarity to maybe
something around 88% by
we don't need to do anything about it so
upset because we just need another
exists
alright so now that we've got that if
statement because collin next line and
now we want to click Next Next area so
we're going to click and the next area
appears next to the center of current
area so something that doesn't change is
this our purpose here on the right to
put this in coming to check its matching
some similarity picking up the other
direction as well so its first set up so
it's only getting the one side 85% by
target all set and resume out again with
the scroll wheel and we want to pick the
next concern along for mac online so we
want to click in this empty space here
fly ok so now we've got a click setup
this so click and move on to the next
area when we move on to the next area we
want to make sure we set out time to
head back to their and up to the next
area when when there's no enemies left
tackle in this area right so come back
to help us if line again for a little
bit of white space in their little bit
easier aid if and we're going to do it
just for an upgrade now so before I like
aids with the check that had decided to
be a highlight of Blues so we're gonna
need to play our game a little bit you
click on a few times get out first
upgrade available right now that we've
got an upgrade available we can now try
and match that if exists
little screenshot here and I want to
select a sketch of this bit of this and
we don't want to get the coins because
the coins will change so let's get to
see eg 0
little blue section him and if it does
exist to make sure simpson similarities
alright
open that up a few matches going on so
that boosted up a bit to say haiti's 88%
by ok so if that exists then we won a
set should I upgrade to true so we're
now setting out should I upgrade to
search and once we know that we should
upgrade we're going to click click click
but it up during the massive delay that
you click the Upgrade button who are
slick same copy pasted that actually
might do that in fact copy paste image
from up here they said in so every save
up in space
maxis correctly yep I mean to say that I
offset somewhere in the middle button
make sure the way we're hitting it right
so quickly and upgrades that will
upgrade and we want to set out time to
Dead two plus two equals one so we were
able to upgrade successfully and there
wasn't any missed upgrades
up on me when I set out clothes for this
statement
else colon
if the pattern was to not exist for the
upgrade then we want to tell it to
either set the time to time to deadly
kozyrev there is no upgrade if it does
exist did exist at some point then we
want to set our clocks back up and said
I upgrade to false alright so if not
should I upgrade so if it didn't exist
after doing a spatter beauty clinics and
we want to set our time to head to equal
there're so we failed to achieve an
upgrade in the amount I'm bookmarking
and will said I should upgrade to echo
thoughts after that so there wasn't any
upgrades existing you want to set to
FALSE then we want to set our should
click for 250 and her back up to 50
times alright so this should be enough
for us to start seeing how things are
working so let's save this call it click
click Save
we're going to click on the enemies
until there's none left in the burned or
until his upgrades available and let's
give it a shot so saved from the start
clicking will do its 50 clicks and might
lose a few clicks here on that just to
leave because of its interaction with
the game and i mean upgrade
like we've got a similarity issue I'm
trying to upgrade things that an
upgradeable so it's Kontrol f1 and have
a look at what it might be
ok so the issue was that the image that
I was trying to find two similar to the
one selected image so let's say this I
just freaked recapture the image using a
little bit more background so let's give
this a shot instead rerun
click and wanted guns clicking should I
upgrade to upgrade again as it still
available by clicking must have missed
it when I was doing its hopes relations
stunts clicking the area's complete
upgrades grades are all done should
moves to the next area which already has
done and that's pretty cool so we've got
a lot of what he now it's clicking and
it's doing it's upgrading and going back
to clicking ones not grades to do I'm
moving on to the next one is two one
problem with that book currently
probably fall on its head in the next
area possibly on the next on the level
10 zone and this is because every five
levels in clicking here is this a boss
has a timed clicking event which means I
but needs to be out of killing quick
enough to be a move on to the next time
I'm doesn't then ok but keep repeating
the same thing over and over again which
will get a stuck in a loop but we can't
win so we need to build that into our
system so as you can see the time going
down now in the middle of the game and
we're not doing enough damage actually
might actually be doing enough damage to
be at this time however as you said
times going down and running out of time
and we don't get to kill it in time
probably 10 times up it keeps repeating
over and over again I'm gonna get stuck
in a loop so we need to combat this when
there's a bus visible we need to make
sure we can go back to the previous
level if we haven't upgraded enough
rights and the script hell yeah I mean
to put in a bus check so I'm gonna come
up here and create another variable
coach bus and bus going to start a false
and down the very bottom when we're
checking out often or upgrades exist and
we're talking again we're going to put a
check in to make sure there's no bus or
there is the bus we should click for
longer or go back to a previous level if
we're not able to kill a quick enough
right so if exists just again but it
exists screenshot and we want to capture
this clock he also want to try and stay
inside the edges of the clock and keep
an update how that we can match to it so
if the clock exists it does I met you
preview pretty similar I was buffed up
two studs to make sure it around 90% why
so if it exists and it's not currently
boss demi 12 said should click for eco
hundred and fifty quicks three times and
no amount which should be enough to take
out a boss in terms of a share and then
we're gonna set out boss variable to
equal true with a capital T
alright we want and I'll if
else if exists how fast i'ma bust time
and its similarity that exists and we
want to do you al
go back to levels are unable to kill the
bus and we've run out of clicks then we
want to go back to the previous low to
get stronger so we're going to click and
we want to copy how click from the
foreword by clicking on the Next Iron
Man copy this whole line actually come
down to where we're clicking and this
time we want to change where the target
of cities so instead of clicking on the
right hand side back on the left to go
back to level ply ok so once you've
clicked the bus to go there are no
longer on the bus level and the previous
alright so this should keep going over
to get strong after defeat the boss but
save this and come back two years and
then go back to the previous sign them
over now script so hit run the sense
that clicking
should upgrade and then she moves up to
the next level to be a bus level it
should at least have his grades won't be
strong enough so we need to get to
upgrades in a row of clicking before we
can go up to the next Sun so that
upgrade should take it to the next Sun
Sweden fail I'm on the bus should
preprocessing that our bus 150 times
we defeat the bus this time and continue
fighting it on the next time you get all
out cold though try upgrading and should
move on to the next Sun should we have
failed however it would have moved back
to the previous son how to move the
stuff to the next Sun cuz we haven't
gotten to upwards so this may pose a
possible issue depending on how come
back his own things that were not fit
enough to achieve getting stronger
up to the bus
anyway start to get the point should
continue to repeat this process until we
move through the game called so I ended
here and that's a script completed
awesome ok that's it for this series I
encourage you to explore the
documentation if there's a specific task
is to complete with single yet and not
sure if the feature exists I wish you
well with your newfound automation power
you have any questions leave it in the
comments and I'll try to answer is
Best's possible don't forget to
subscribe thanks for watching