welcome to school Exeter number three
additional automation in this video we
look at some of the fancy important
output to securely access gives us and
also will look at selection in patent
that allows us to a conditions to
Asakura scripts everybody have all
slides is anchored available no
description interacting with the user
can be quite important and is a great
way for us to her now conditional
automation skills you in school yikes
ever its previous versions is some nice
Gy pop-ups that can give information to
the user or receive information from
them
sex scandals this really well and is as
simple as it gets to use alright let's
look at the six functions available to
us the first three output boxes will pop
up which does exactly that sounds
created dialogue with extra give it an
optional title as well as an OK button
that will close it we have pop era which
is like a public however shows areas and
alongside the text we then have asked
which is the public once again rise the
user with a yes or no decision we can
then used to determine what we do from
that the second half input pups which
allows to receive input from the user of
the script the input function will give
a simple input box with an OK and Cancel
buttons we can also optionally give this
window a prompt such as what is your
favorite number we can also optionally
give it a default answer an optional
title for the window and we can
optionally said hidden tutored turning
into a possible hiding input characters
we then have input text which works
similar import covers a much bigger
bucks and can be customized to be even
bigger in size
finally we have select which is my
personal favorite provide the public
with a drop down and the user can select
from a list of options we provide such
as whether there was to add subtract
multiply or divide alright let's give
these you are boxes are trying to get
comfortable so we can use them later in
a decision-making so we come over to
securely and let's try tried out so
creative a variable code name so quickly
named I'm gonna make that echo input
open parenthesis in courts were gonna
put up now text that we want to put in
the input sir and your name being closed
up the quotes and closing parenthesis
and then let's use the pop-up
pop-up function in a print disease and
we're going to acquire its color and
then we're going to add on the named the
end name.com are making title the box
below
you give the national title which will
make the proper called heller and it'll
say hello to the name that was ended
previously alright let's try out input
text field so who do some text as a
variable in Astoria last text
echo input input text with a capital T
pregnancies and text quotes close
princes and then that's proper Panera
and will pop out the Sun text service
era through and apparel do close courts
and the some tax return to the end
rights that should give us a good look
of opera does right now let's try out
the select input type so first we need
to create a couple of options so my
options can be a variable named go to
store all in my options with heparin
equals open up parentheses and in courts
which one was the first option is coming
to includes
three words for you cards come up and
500 closed up a parenthesis and we have
a couple of options let's now stop the
result of what the user pics so it is
going to be what these pics with the
select dropdown because select and
inside the Select were going to tell
them pick a number and then we're going
to set the options for a select to echo
my options because of a parenthesis cope
right now we can use the Pope asked
output and what this does is it gives
them a yes or no answer and we can store
that yes or no answer inside of a
variable so call a verbal choice that's
gonna equal prop ask and inside here we
can say did you select and then we can
add on the number that they'd like to
return result a simple question mark on
the end
closed off that since you asked him did
you select the result they previously so
should be yes but just illustrate how it
works in commercial pilots get the save
and call it an important test
saver and its leaders
runs on a popup saying enter your name
so it's jobs ok then we get a popup that
says he'll address and the title of it
is however as we set up and then we've
got our textbooks so this is some text
so let's and doesn't text you today and
then hit enter a title he doesn't text
ok and we get asked all the era so this
is now peres type says hello how are you
today so don't make much sense but we
have to see how it works and then we get
a SELECT statements got a list of
options
12345 so you can pick a number so that's
good for me OK and then we've got asked
asked says did you select for a yes or
no other than to say yes and a program
finishes so if we wanted to we could do
it another popup that says whether they
said yes honor for the pop ask but we
just move on from here to right now 12
selection I'm going to try and move over
this pretty loudly as I did recommend
some basic plot no programming
experience ok so that makes decisions we
use the if statement it allows it to
check if an expression is true or false
if it's true we do something otherwise
FALSE we've done important to notice the
palestinians intends to decide when kurt
is inside of it if statement this could
be a single space just a one time with
four as it makes it easier to read also
note the colon on the end of the line to
expect intend on the next line now these
expressions we check result in either
true or false
for this we have comparison operators we
can check if somebody's equal or
something is not equal began taking
things for granted
less than etcetera a place to couple of
examples at the bottom here five is less
than those ten is greater than or equal
to 10 is true
five is equal to one is false and you
can solely place true or false
as an expression and it will work all
right now we know how to use the if
statement let's look at two other
statements that go hand in hand with
this statement is that on to the end of
the F sort of the expression is church
do something else if it's both do this
instead it's fairly simple finally if
statement the statement allows it to
check another expression if the first
one was falls so if true do something
else if this is church do something
different
house do this instead we can combine as
many elephants in one if statement as we
like
ok now finally back to some scripting
let's create a calculator automation
again this time however will ask the the
beginning if they wish to add subtract
multiply or divide also to mix it up
let's use the number five instead of one
right so we come back to school here and
will create a new document includes all
right so we wanna ask them if they want
to add subtract multiply and divide
let's special am so create a variable
called modes not gonna equal couple of
of us options so I first one can be had
for words come up and we can do some
clothes guards come up quotes moll
multiply and divide words close up at
Apple alright so goddamn words let's now
ask the use of what they were 11 under
so called a result option and options
can echo select to any used to select
winner
what would you like to question mark and
then passing out options is going to eat
cool emergence was up a parenthesis
certainly we've got from the user book
what kind of action they want to do the
arithmetic know we can continue doing
what we did last to do so click the Stop
gun so let's use the Quick stopped on 70
could stop by them you wanna wait for
the such but that's just copy from the
last the last one so it's not copy wait
type the same copy I'll wait really
titled pasted in so we're going to click
the start button
we're going to wait for the search
button come up we're going to typing
calc and press the Enter key I'm going
to wait for the calculator a popup once
calculated popped up we can click the
five buttons copy right click
click out a calculator and we want to
click click on this and target upset me
five button to apply ok so now we're
cooking the five button and now we can
start writing out if so this is what we
choose but we're going to add subtract
multiply or divide so if if option so
the option that they use a slight to the
star is equal to double double equal
sign words
square brackets is there a close call
back its so if the option they selected
was able to the first married to weaken
semicolon Collins aren't going to call
in to go down to the next line and if so
then we're going to click and copy of
previous line to click and we're going
to click on the target offset of the
plus symbol so we're going to add a
reply
take pictures to add going to add never
came back out to the first line and do
so we're going to be checking again with
another if statement the first one was
full so they didn't choose I'd be going
to check with the option is able to
merge
square bracket 100 square bracket so the
first murder was to see the secondary
technically mister subtract in person
and i click here and pick a target of
said instead of trust this time it's
entrapped apply okay and then
do one more else is equal to the Marines
square bracket to cause we're back and
we're going to click and this time we're
going to be clicking the multiplier
because we did add subtract multiply and
divide
target offset this time is for you
multiply 15 ok all right and now we need
to have one moment is gonna be out this
time so if every other option is false
then they must have chosen the divide
button so else colon in place now
quickly and this time we're going to
start offset to the divide simple y ok
right so now we've got out if statements
are based on what the user selected this
time we're going to either add subtract
multiply or divide if it is finished
running we're going to eat five button
again outside of a sore back on the
first line 59 rather upset 25 again he
got there because I copied that previous
previous five calculation 5 click
another and then we're going to equal
sign us up said i target all set to the
equal sign apply ok we're going to
seventeen lines of code you can save
this so safe and this time we'll call it
felt to a second revision can't save it
and then let's give it a shot so we're
going to set up a merge and asked him
which murdered like I'm going to run the
script was given a shot what would you
like to do add subtract multiply divide
let's go with multiple ok to take over
but couldn't find the image to the stop
on
down now seems to be struggling to find
stop its remove stop by before Markakis
we know that works as the back in
multiple I K
found a stop on typing calculator
calculator five times five equals 25
program work correctly I was struggling
to match that's not my name is too
sensitive and it's happening again this
time we want to attract ok runs
calculator 5-5 equals zero there and
Moshe will track the divide so this is
an hour else statement ok morning
occurred 5/5 he calls to be 11 cool
after working correctly
ok that's it for this video we can now
make choices that interact with the use
of this would become a necessity in the
upcoming videos
the next thing we'll be looking at is
looping automation you have any
questions leave it in the comments and
I'll try to answer as best possible
don't forget to subscribe thanks for
watching